const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following cavities is present in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding Kluver-Bucy syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Hyper-sexuality","bool":false},{"option":"Hyper-orality","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of emotions","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a superficial reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctival reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Plantar reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is associated with an enlargement of the posterior cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Holoprosencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Arnold-Chiari type I","bool":false},{"option":"Dandy-walker syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Arnold-Chiari type II","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a deep tendon reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Biceps reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctival reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Ankle reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Brachioradialis reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Patellar reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which cranial nerve nucleus is present at the level of the superior colliculus?","answers":[{"option":"Facial motor nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal nucleus of vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which one of the following is a function of the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":true},{"option":"Increased GIT motility","bool":false},{"option":"Defecation","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which one of the following structures is the largest component of the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"The molecular layer of the cerebellar cortex does not contain which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells","bool":true},{"option":"Neuroglia","bool":false},{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false},{"option":"Parallel fibers of granular cells axons","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Neurotransmitters (catecholamines) are mainly derived from which amino acid?","answers":[{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following regarding oligodendroglia is true?","answers":[{"option":"Supporting cells of PNS","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Can myelinate more than one axon per cell","bool":true},{"option":"Helps in forming pia meningeal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Helps in blood brain barrier formation/maintenance","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What signs and symptoms will be observed as a consequence of a lesion in Wernicke's area?","answers":[{"option":"Inability to produce fluent speech","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to read or write","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to appreciate texture of objects","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to understand written or spoken words","bool":true},{"option":"Inability to interpret sounds","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is an indolamine derived from tryptophan?","answers":[{"option":"Prostaglandin","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene","bool":false},{"option":"Chitin","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Where does the superior sagittal sinus drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Longitudinal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Right transverse sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sinusoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoidal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is another name for the hindbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common and dangerous site of thrombosis?","answers":[{"option":"Superior petrosal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior saggital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior saggital sinus","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is an autoimmune disease affecting the nicotinic acetylcholine receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD)","bool":false},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":true},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Guillain-Barr√© syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Agenesis of the corpus callosum is associated with which of the following symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of motor contrtol","bool":false},{"option":"Mental retardation","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of speech","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of sensory control","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of coordination","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Subdural space is located between which of the following layers?","answers":[{"option":"Pia mater and arachnoid mater","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Arachnoid mater and dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"Dura mater and pia mater","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"The brain magnetic resonance image (MRI) of an 8-year-old child shows a bat-wing deformity. Which condition is the most likely cause of this?","answers":[{"option":"Polymicrogyria","bool":false},{"option":"Neuronal heterotopia","bool":false},{"option":"Lissencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Holoprosencephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Agenesis of corpus callosum","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common disease in extrapyramidal tracts?","answers":[{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Fragile X syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Wilson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following nerve cell bodies is NOT present in the posterior gray column of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Substantia gelatinosa","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus proprius","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral afferent nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nuclei regulates circadian rhythms?","answers":[{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which part of the brain must be blocked to produce an enlargement of the third and lateral ventricles on a child's radiograph?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following structures are constituents of the limbic system?","answers":[{"option":"Pulvinar of the thalamus and substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Subcallosal, cingulate and parahippocampal gyri, hippocampal formation, amygdaloid nucleus, mammillary body and anterior thalamic nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Amygdaloid nucleus, red nucleus, and vestibular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Cingulate gyrus and the uncus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampal formation","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"In neonates, what causes acute pyogenic meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Listeria monocytogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Toxoplasma gondii","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Necator americanus","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Lacunar infarcts may occur due to the occlusion of which of the following vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Venules","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Small arteries","bool":true},{"option":"Aorta","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is a sign of Huntington's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Enlarged posterior fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Resting tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Cogwheel rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":true},{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What does uncal herniation cause?","answers":[{"option":"Chewing difficulties","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent shaped lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor paralysis","bool":true},{"option":"Breathing cessation","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney disease","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following structures cannot be appreciated at the level of the decussation of pyramids?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal tract of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":true},{"option":"Accessory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is not an opioid receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Œº","bool":false},{"option":"Œ∫","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha","bool":true},{"option":"Zeta","bool":false},{"option":"Œ¥","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Morphine is used for relief from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Referred pain","bool":false},{"option":"Pain in kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Chest pain","bool":true},{"option":"Pain in limbs","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Where does the cerebellum receive information concerning muscle movement from?","answers":[{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What are the phagocytotic cells of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Satellite cells","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Damage to which of the following results in the loss of pain sensation?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following secretes cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Pia mater","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid plexus","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Light touch sensations are lost when which of the following is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following tracts is spared in anterior cord syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Corticobulbar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Pyramids in the medulla are formed by which of the following fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Corticospinal fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Rubrospinal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Corticobulbar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Corticopontine fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Parkinson's disease involves degeneration of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus striatum","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is responsible for normal maintenance of tone and equilibrium?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is dopamine synthesized from?","answers":[{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the function of the vestibular nucleus present in the brainstem?","answers":[{"option":"REM sleep and non-REM sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory system","bool":false},{"option":"Antigravity muscles to maintain equilibrium","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiovascular system","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"According to the World Health Organization, how long is the loss of cerebral function for it to be called a stroke?","answers":[{"option":"More than 3 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"Atleast 3 days","bool":false},{"option":"More than 24 hours","bool":true},{"option":"Less than 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"More than 1 hour","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding dural venous sinuses?","answers":[{"option":"They are devoid of smooth muscles","bool":false},{"option":"The flow is bidirectional","bool":false},{"option":"They are present between the arachnoid and dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"They have no valves","bool":false},{"option":"They are lined by endothelium","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"A patient presents with right-sided hemiplegia and loss of speech. Upon examination, both of his eyes deviate to the left. Damage to which artery can present with these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"In bacterial meningitis, compared to normal cerebrospinal fluid, which of the following is found to be typically decreased?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Cardiac and vasomotor centers are located in which of the following structures of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following does not form the roof of the inferior horn of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Pes hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Stria terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Tail of caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Tapetum of corpus callosum","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Where is the sensory nucleus of the trigeminal nerve present?","answers":[{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"C5 spinal level","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":true},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following structures is present at the level of the oculomotor nerve nucleus?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior olivary nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncles","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Facial colliculus is formed by which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Trochlear nerve as it loops over facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve as it loops over principal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve as it loops over hypoglossal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve as it loops over facial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve as it loops over the abducens nucleus","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which artery is not part of the circle of Willis?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which sinus does not drain at the occipital confluence?","answers":[{"option":"Superior sagittal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior petrosal sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which peripheral nerve is myelinated by oligodendrocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which one of the following structures is not part of the sub limbic cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Septal nuclei","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following are the only climbing fibers in the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Reticulocerebellar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Olivocerebellar fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Rubrocerebellar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Pontocerebellar fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is a precursor of epinephrine?","answers":[{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Lysine","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"In what form does the brain mainly utilize energy?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Fats","bool":false},{"option":"DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Heat","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Lesion of the supraoptic nucleus results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased prolactin production","bool":false},{"option":"Increased volume of urine","bool":true},{"option":"Increased oxytocin production","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased volume of urine","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersexuality","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which cranial nerve damage will cause respiratory issues?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Occulomotor nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which cranial nerve will most likely be injured in an anterior cranial fossa fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the function of the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Sense of proprioception","bool":false},{"option":"Coordination of motor functions","bool":false},{"option":"Speech control","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic control","bool":true},{"option":"Memory formation","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which nerve passes through foramen rotundum?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nucleus acts as an osmoreceptor?","answers":[{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Preoptic nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is the correct statement regarding the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Widespread damage to bilateral somatosensory area 1 causes astereognosis","bool":false},{"option":"Somatosensory area 1 is located in the precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"The visual cortex lies in the temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary auditory cortex relates perception of sound with past experiences","bool":true},{"option":"Broca area is area 3, 1, and 2","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"The visual pathway passes through which part of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Sublenticular part","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolenticular part","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"The auditory pathway is linked to which part of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Sublentiform part","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolentiform part","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following structures is involved in sleep and awakening?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":true},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguus","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What are the cardinal signs of Parkinson‚Äôs disease?","answers":[{"option":"Resting tremor, bradykinesia, muscle rigidity","bool":true},{"option":"Myoclonus, athetosis, muscle rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Essential tremor, bradykinesia, chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Resting tremor, postural instability, and hemiballismus","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the lateral medullary syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"There may be analgesia and thermoanesthesia on the contralateral side of the face","bool":false},{"option":"The nucleus ambiguus of the same side may be damaged","bool":true},{"option":"There may be evidence of seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral trunk and extremity hypalgesia and thermoanesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"May be caused by a thrombosis of the anterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Histamine is formed in which of the following steps?","answers":[{"option":"Decarboxylation of histidine","bool":true},{"option":"Deamination of methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxylation of proline","bool":false},{"option":"Methylation of serine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosylation of glycine","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following terms refers to disease constantly present in a small population?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":true},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false},{"option":"Outbreak","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is most likely to result from a disruption of blood supply to the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Vascular dementia","bool":true},{"option":"Frontotemporal dementia","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's dementia","bool":false},{"option":"Dementia with Lewy bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic dementia","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following neurotransmitters is involved in the conduction of superficial pain?","answers":[{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoactive intestinal peptide","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Weakness of the lateral rectus occurs from damage to which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following statement is correct regarding nerve fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Blood vessels run in the endoneurium","bool":true},{"option":"The perineurium surrounds many nerve bundles into one nerve fiber (called the nerve proper)","bool":false},{"option":"The toughest part is the perineurium","bool":false},{"option":"The epineurium encloses a single nerve fiber and adheres it to other nerve fibers to form a nerve bundle","bool":false},{"option":"The endoneurium surrounds the nerve bundles","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a normal constituent of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"K+","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which nucleus receives information about proprioception from the head and neck?","answers":[{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of the trigeminal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of the trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Principal pontine nucleus of the trigeminal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which region is compressed in tonsillar herniation?","answers":[{"option":"Lumbar spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical spinal cord","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following symptoms are not observed in cerebellar disease?","answers":[{"option":"Slurred speech","bool":false},{"option":"Rigidity","bool":true},{"option":"Unsteady gait","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthria","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired coordination","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is not true about the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior nucleus controls sympathetic system","bool":false},{"option":"Preoptic nucleus releases GnRH","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus controls circadian rhythms","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior nucleus controls sympathetic system","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral nucleus controls hunger","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following pairs of muscles is involved in shrugging of the shoulders and the movement of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid and longus capitus","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius and levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Scalene and platysma","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid and trapezius","bool":true},{"option":"Trapezius and platysma","bool":false}]}]
export default arr